Guide to the Records of Graham Windham 1804-2011 MS 2916
New-York Historical Society
- Series I - Orphan Asylum Society/Graham Home for Children, 1806-1981 (bulk 1806-1977), 11428
  - Subseries I.3 - Annual Reports 1806-1977, 11432
    For annual reports of the Society for the Relief of Half Orphans and Destitute Children/Windham Child Care, please see Series II.
    For annual reports of Graham Windham, formed in 1977 by the merger of the Graham Home and the Windham Child Care, please see Series III.
    - Annual Reports, Constitution and By-Laws, 1806-1828; 11484 (Volume 19)
    - Annual Reports, Constitution and By-Laws (including handwritten inserts), 1815-1836; 11474 (Volume 20)
    - Annual Reports 1837-1860, with An Address and Prayer on Laying the Cornerstone 1823, and A Discourse on the Death of Mrs. Sarah Hoffman, First Directress, 1821, 1821-1860; 11475 (Volume 21)
    - Origin and History of the Orphan Asylum Society Vol. I (reprint of annual reports and other documents 1806-1857), circa 1896; 11476 (Volume 22)
    - Origin and History of the Orphan Asylum Society Vol. I (reprint of annual reports and other documents 1806-1857), circa 1896; 11477 (Volume 23)
    - Origin and History of the Orphan Asylum Society Vol. I (reprint of annual reports and other documents 1806-1857), circa 1896; 11478 (Volume 24)
    - Origin and History of the Orphan Asylum Society Vol. II (reprint of annual reports 1858-1895 and other documents 1807-1822), circa 1896; 11479 (Volume 25)
    - Origin and History of the Orphan Asylum Society Vol. II (reprint of annual reports 1858-1895 and other documents 1807-1822), circa 1896; 11480 (Volume 26)
    - Origin and History of the Orphan Asylum Society Vol. II (reprint of annual reports 1858-1895 and other documents 1807-1822), circa 1896; 11481 (Volume 27)
    - Origin and History of the Orphan Asylum Society Vol. II (reprint of annual reports 1858-1895 and other documents 1807-1822), circa 1896; 11482 (Volume 28)
    - Annual Report with Constitution and By-Laws, 1823; 11485 (Offsite-box 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1833-1854; 11486 (Offsite-box 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1855-1871; 11487 (Offsite-box 3)
    - Annual Reports, 1872-1879; 11488 (Offsite-box 4)
    - Annual Reports, 1880-1885; 11489 (Offsite-box 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1887-1892; 11490 (Offsite-box 6)
    - Annual Reports, 1893-1901; 11491 (Offsite-box 7)
    - Annual Reports, 1902-1909; 11492 (Offsite-box 8)
    - Annual Reports, 1910-1914; 11493 (Offsite-box 9)
    - Annual Reports, 1915-1922; 11494 (Offsite-box 10)
    - Annual Reports, 1923-1929; 11495 (Offsite-box 11)
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1946, 1949, 1959, 1965-1967, 1973, 1975-1977; 11497 (Offsite-box 12)
    - Annual Report, 1959; 50087 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
    - Annual Report, 1970; 50415 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
  - Subseries I.4 - Financial Records, 1808-1957, 1820-1956; 11435
    The subseries contains financial records (1808-1957, bulk 1820-1956) of the Orphan Asylum Society (1806-1929), renamed the Graham School (1929-1950) and Graham Home for Children (1950-1977), arranged by type and in rough chronological order. Most of the records are handwritten in bound volumes. Loose records are arranged in boxes after the volumes. The records are not inclusive. The names for types of records are not consistent. It is not always clear who created the records. Some records were kept by the Treasurer, some by the Assistant Treasurer, and some may have been kept by the Secretary, a board member, or the Superintendent.
    Financial Records are closed to the public for a term of one hundred years from their date of creation. Records older than one hundred years are open for research.
    - Orphan Asylum Account Book [Treasurer's Cash Expenses], 1808-1821; 11504 (Volume 29)
    - Orphan Asylum Account Book [Treasurer's Cash Expenses], 1821-1827; 11505 (Volume 30)
    - Treasurer's Account Book [Cash Expenses], 1825-1838; 11506 (Volume 31)
    - Treasurer's Account Book [Cash Expenses], 1839-1853; 11507 (Volume 32)
    - Treasurer's Account Book [Cash Expenses], 1853-1867; 11508 (Volume 33)
    - Treasurer's Account Book [Cash Expenses], 1867-1881; 11509 (Volume 34)
    - Treasurer's Account Book [Cash Expenses], 1881-1888; 11510 (Volume 35)
    - Treasurer's Expense Book, 1875-1884; 11513 (Volume 36)
    - Treasurer's Expense Book, 1885-1897; 11514 (Volume 37)
    - Treasurer's Cash Book, 1890-1896; 11515 (Volume 38)
    - Treasurer's Cash Book [Oversize], 1895-1901; 11516 (Volume 39)
    - Treasurer's Cash Book [Oversize], 1906-1912; 11517 (Volume 40)
    - Treasurer's Cash Book [Oversize], 1912-1917; 11518 (Volume 41)
    - Treasurer's Cash Book [Oversize], 1922-1923; 11519 (Volume 42)
    - Receipt Book, 1820-1830; 11520 (Volume 43)
    - Receipt Book, 1839-1853; 11521 (Volume 44)
    - Receipt Book, 1853-1857; 11522 (Volume 45)
    - Expenses/Provisions, 1865-1868; 11523 (Volume 46)
    - Expenses/Provisions, 1865-1871; 11524 (Volume 47)
    - Expenses/Provisions, 1871-1874; 11525 (Volume 48)
    - Expenses/Provisions, 1872-1874; 11526 (Volume 49)
    - Donations, 1814-1818; 11527 (Volume 50)
    - Donations, 1831-1852; 11528 (Volume 51)
    - Property bought and sold, and estate donations, 1833-1869; 11529 (Volume 52)
    - Subscription Book, 1820-1829; 11530 (Volume 53)
    - Subscription Book, 1845-1855; 11531 (Volume 54)
    - Subscription Book, 1857-1899; 11532 (Volume 55)
    - Agent's/Assistant Treasurer's Cash Book, 1869-1875; 11533 (Volume 56)
    - Assistant Treasurer's Letter Book, 1896-1906; 11534 (Volume 57)
    - Rentals Collected, 1896-1904; 11535 (Volume 58)
    - Building Account - Cash Book, 1901-1903; 11536 (Volume 59)
    - Building Account - Journal, 1901-1903; 11537 (Volume 60)
    - Expenses, 1903-1904; 11538 (Volume 61)
    - Expenses, 1919-1925; 11539 (Volume 62)
    - Receipts and Payments, 1919-1925; 11540 (Volume 63)
    - Expenses, 1925-1940; 11541 (Volume 64)
    - Expenses, 1925-1931; 11542 (Volume 65)
    - Expenses, 1931-1937; 11543 (Volume 66)
    - Expenses, 1937-1943; 11544 (Volume 67)
    - Expenses, 1943-1947; 11545 (Volume 68)
    - Assistant Treasurer Cash Book, 1914-1920; 11546 (Volume 69)
    - Assistant Treasurer Cash Book, 1920-1929; 11547 (Volume 70)
    - Assistant Treasurer Cash Book, 1929-1936; 11548 (Volume 71)
    - Assistant Treasurer Cash Book, 1937-1943; 11549 (Volume 72)
    - Assistant Treasurer Cash Book, 1943-1948; 11550 (Volume 73)
    - Assistant Treasurer Cash Book, 1948-1951; 11551 (Volume 74)
    - Assistant Treasurer Cash Book, 1952-1955; 11552 (Volume 75)
    - Assistant Treasurer Cash Book, 1955-1957; 11553 (Volume 76)
    - Assistant Treasurer Journal, 1914-1929; 11554 (Volume 77)
    - Assistant Treasurer Journal, 1929-1953; 11555 (Volume 78)
    - Assistant Treasurer Ledger, 1920-1929; 11556 (Volume 79)
    - Assistant Treasurer Ledger, 1929-1941; 11557 (Volume 80)
    - Assistant Treasurer Ledger, 1942-1950; 11558 (Volume 81)
    - Children's Accounts, 1914-1920; 11559 (Volume 82)
    - Children's Accounts, 1920-1935; 11560 (Volume 83)
    - Children's Accounts, 1935-1943; 11561 (Volume 84)
    - Children's Accounts, 1944-1948; 11562 (Volume 85)
    - Private Maintenance, 1923-1929; 11563 (Volume 86)
    - Private Maintenance, 1929-1934; 11564 (Volume 87)
    - Private Maintenance, 1946-1947; 11565 (Volume 88)
    - Maintenance Public and Private, 1934-1937; 11566 (Volume 89)
    - Maintenance Public and Private, 1937-1941; 11567 (Volume 90)
    - Maintenance Public and Private, 1941-1945; 11568 (Volume 91)
    - Public Maintenance, 1940-1947; 11569 (Volume 92)
    - Cash Receipts, Maintenance Receipts, Dun Fund, 1929-1951; 11570 (Volume 93)
    - Cash Receipts and Disbursements, 1947-1949; 11571 (Volume 94)
    - Cash Receipts and Disbursements, 1950-1951; 11572 (Volume 95)
    - Cash Receipts and Disbursements, 1956; 11573 (Volume 96)
    - Mrs. Bell's Special Appeals Ledger, 1949-1956; 11574 (Volume 97)
    - Mrs. Bell's Special Appeals Receipts and Disbursements, 1953-1956; 11575 (Volume 98)
    - Check Stubs, 1939-1952; 11576 (Volume 99)
    - Trinity Church Cemetery Plot Deeds, circa 1869; 11578 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
    - Check stubs, 1896-1906; 11579 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
    - Assistant Treasurer and Treasurer's Statements, 1899-1900; 11580 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
    - OAS Payroll, 1900-1913; 11581 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
    - Treasurer's and Assistant Treasurer's Statements, 1910-1913; 11582 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
    - Audits, 1910-1918; 11583 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
    - Treasurer's and Assistant Treasurer's Statements, 1914-1918; 11584 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
    - Brown Legacy, 1917; 11585 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
    - Bank books, circa 1890-1920; 11586 (Offsite-box 14)
    - Check stubs, 1910-1912; 11587 (Offsite-box 14)
    - Financial statements, 1910-1912; 11588 (Offsite-box 14)
    - Architect's Financial Records, Hastings-on-Hudson Property, 1901-1902; 11589 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
    - OAS Audits, 1919-1921, 1931, 1932, 1936; 11590 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
    - Investments, 1940, 1956; 11591 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
    - OAS Financial Reports, 1943-1945; 11592 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
    - Graham legacy from Mary Stuart - Court Petition, 1943; 11593 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
    - May Taylor Fund, 1948-1965; 11594 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
    - Statements of Securities, 1952, 1954; 11595 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
    - Audits and Bank Statements, 1956; 11596 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8)
    - OAS Audits, 1937-1956; 11597 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
    - OAS Accounts, 1940-1941; 11598 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)
    - OAS Accounts, 1945-1946; 11599 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 2)
    - OAS Accounts, 1947, 1949; 11600 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3)
    - OAS Accounts, 1950-1951; 11601 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 4)
    - OAS Accounts, 1952; 11602 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5)
    - OAS Accounts, 1953; 11603 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 6)
    - OAS Accounts, 1954; 11604 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 7)
    - OAS Accounts, 1955; 11605 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 8)
  - Subseries I.5 - Committee Reports and Other Inspections, 1848-1966, 11606
    The subseries consists of five volumes of reports of the Visitor's Commitee (1842-1892), followed by two volumes of records and reports of the Investigating Committee (1900-1905), followed by one volume of records of the Correspondence Committee (1903-1922). The women of the Visitor's Committee visited the asylum regularly and reported their observations to the board. The Investigating Committee appears to have performed follow-up visits to children who had left the asylum, as well as investigations of children in the asylum. The Correspondence Committee recorded information about, and correspondence with, selected children who had left the asylum, following their lives for many years.
    The volumes are followed by folders containing an inspection report by the State Board of Social Welfare (1935-36) forwarded to the Board, and a bound report of a visiting committee to the Board (1966).
    Reports in this subseries are closed to the public for a term of one hundred years from their date of creation. Records older than one hundred years are open for research.
    - Reports of the Visitor's Committee, 1848-1860; 11609 (Volume 100)
    - Reports of the Visitor's Committee, 1861-1872; 11610 (Volume 101)
    - Reports of the Visitor's Committee, 1872-1882; 11611 (Volume 102)
    - Reports of the Visitor's Committee, 1882-1886; 11612 (Volume 103)
    - Reports of the Visitor's Committee, 1892; 11613 (Volume 104)
    - Minutes [Reports] of the Investigating Committee, 1900-1905; 11614 (Volume 105)
    - Records of the Investigating Committee, 1900-1905; 11615 (Volume 106)
    - Records of the Correspondence Committee, 1903-1922; 11616 (Volume 107)
    - State Board of Social Welfare Inspection Report, 1935-1936; 11624 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 10)
    - Report of the Findings and Recommendations of a Special Visiting Committee to the Board of Trustees, 1966 April; 11623 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.6 - Superintendent, School, and Children's Records, 1806-1979, 11436
    The subseries contains records kept by the Superintendent of the Orphan Asylum Society, who was responsible for the day-to-day running of the OAS, and also contains other records relating to children and the school. Most of the material is in the form of bound volumes. Volumes are arranged by type, and then chronologically. Some additional volumes and loose materials are arrranged in folders after the volumes.
    The titles of admission books/registers are not consistent, and some dates overlap. Some volumes are narrative records, with stories about each child, and these are labeled "narrative" in the container list. Others are chronological or alphabetical and provide demographic data. The "Superintendent's Journals" provide daily narrative reports of events at the OAS.
    The records in this subseries are closed to the public for a term of one hundred years from their date of creation. Records older than one hundred years are open for research.
    - Orphan Asylum Register (Chronological, with alphabetical index. Lists indentures), 1806-1830; 11617 (Volume 108)
    - Orphan Asylum Register (Alphabetical), circa 1806-1890; 11618 (Volume 109)
    - Admissions (Alphabetical and Chronological), 1806-1979; 11619 (Volume 110)
    - Admissions (Alphabetical), circa 1818-1842; 11620 (Volume 111)
    - Admissions (Alphabetical), circa 1819-1857; 11621 (Volume 112)
    - Admissions (Chronological), 1849-1895; 11622 (Volume 113)
    - Admissions and Discharges (chronological), 1925-1959; 11625 (Volume 114)
    - Discharges (alphabetical), circa 1807-1842; 11626 (Volume 115)
    - Discharges (alphabetical), circa 1810-1948; 11627 (Volume 116)
    - Discharges (chronological), 1889-1909; 11628 (Volume 117)
    - Discharges (chronological), 1902-1941; 11629 (Volume 118)
    - Discharges 1902-1904 (chronological), Tardiness and Height/Weight Records circa 1905, circa 1902-1905; 11630 (Volume 119)
    - Discharges (chronological), 1941-1970; 11631 (Volume 120)
    - Superintendent's Journal, 1845-1860; 11743 (Volume 121)
    - Superintendent's Journal, 1861-1884; 11744 (Volume 122)
    - Superintendent's Journal, 1884-1889; 11745 (Volume 123)
    - Superintendent's Journal, 1889-1902; 11746 (Volume 124)
    - Superintendent's Journal, 1902-1916; 11747 (Volume 125)
    - Superintendent's Journal, 1916-1933; 11748 (Volume 126)
    - Superintendent's Journal, 1933-1949; 11749 (Volume 127)
    - History of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1846-1919; 11750 (Volume 128)
    - History of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1919-1944; 11751 (Volume 129)
    - History of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1944-1962; 11752 (Volume 130)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1864-1884; 11753 (Volume 131)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1864-1884; 11754 (Volume 132)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1884-1895; 11755 (Volume 133)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1895-1908; 11756 (Volume 134)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1908-1915; 11757 (Volume 135)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1915-1926; 11758 (Volume 136)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1920-1933; 11759 (Volume 137)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1926-1934; 11760 (Volume 138)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1934-1940; 11761 (Volume 139)
    - Histories of Children (Admissions Narratives), 1940-1946; 11762 (Volume 140)
    - Daily Attendance (by gender) and other records, 1838-1850; 11763 (Volume 141)
    - Superintendent's Record of Visitors (alphabetical), circa 1897-1904; 11764 (Volume 142)
    - Visitor's Register (chronological), 1902-1929; 11765 (Volume 143)
    - Theft Book (record of children stealing), 1907-1921; 11766 (Volume 144)
    - Student Records (roll book), 1907-1911; 11767 (Volume 145)
    - Attendance Record (roll book), 1907-1908; 11886 (Volume 145A)
    - Provision Book, circa 1910; 11795 (Volume 145B)
    - IQ Test ca. 1911/Children's Records 1909-1915, 11768 (Volume 146)
    - Application Book (narratives), 1921-1932; 11769 (Volume 147)
    - Children's Grades, 1929-1932; 11770 (Volume 148)
    - Children's Grades, circa 1932-1939; 11771 (Volume 149)
    - Children's Grades, 1938-1944; 11772 (Volume 150)
    - Children's Grades, 1944-1947; 11773 (Volume 151)
    - Children's Grades, 1946-1949; 11774 (Volume 152)
    - Alumni in the Armed Services, 1931-1943; 11776 (Volume 153)
    - Alumni Addresses, circa 1932; 11777 (Volume 154)
    - Birthday Book, 1941-1967; 11778 (Volume 155)
    - Minutes of General Council Meetings (Children's Self-Government), 1949-1952; 11779 (Volume 156)
    - Personal Diary of a (male) Superintendent or Teacher, 1887; 11780 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1)
    - Completed Authorization for Admission and Application for Admission, and Blank Surrender Form, 1889, 1910, and undated; 11781 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 2)
    - Roll Books (4), 1912-1923; 11782 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
    - Roll Books (3), 1928-1939; 11783 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
    - Graham School Boys in Service, 1943; 11784 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
    - Conduct marks, 1948-1949; 11785 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
    - Class Record, 1953; 11786 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
    - Cottage Roll Book with children's names and birthdays, circa 1950-1969; 11787 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
    - Daily Census Reports, 1970; 11788 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
  - Subseries I.7 - Other Administrative Records, circa 1806-1981, 11577
    The subseries consists of eight folders of documents followed by one volume, containing various records retained by the OAS/Graham Home. Materials include a letter to the Orphan Asylum (1892) requesting a baby girl by mail and a thank you note from the Director of the Menagerie of the Department of Public Parks thanking the boys of the Orphan Asylum for donating a screech owl. Both of these letters had been framed and displayed by the agency; they have now been removed from their frames for the purpose of conservation. Other materials in the subseries include a Board of Trustees manual, informational documents about the OAS, and employee records.
    - List of workmen on orphanage (original document, matted), circa 1806-1807; 11873 (Box OS1, Folder 2)
    - Thank you note to boys from Menagerie Director, 1888 November 24; 11816 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Orphan Asylum Requesting Baby, 1892 August 5; 11817 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 11)
    - Lists of employees, circa 1934-1965; 11789 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 12)
    - Typescript report on Graham School with attached construction paper silhouettes and photograph (unknown creator), 1955; 11790 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 13)
    - 5-page fact sheet, 1956; 11791 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 14)
    - History of the Charter and Charter Changes, 1957; 11792 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 15)
    - Board of Trustees Manual, 1973; 11793 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 11794 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 17)
    - Employee Record Book, circa 1950-1981; 11796 (Volume 157)
  - Subseries I.8 - Printed Matter, 1817-1977, 11438
    The subseries consists of ten folders of brochures, pamphlets, programs, and newsletters, arranged by date, followed by published reports and books by administrators of the OAS/Graham School, and books by and/or about the OAS and its founders.
    - Fund-Raising Brochures, Pamphlets and Flyers, circa 1865-1977; 11798 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising brochures and pamphlets, circa 1930-1973; 50216 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
    - Newsletter - Orphanage Messenger No. 17, 1919 July; 11797 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
    - Graham School Postcard, circa 1950's; 50217 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
    - 100 Years Certificate and 150th Anniversary Invitation and Program, 1951-1956; 11799 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 5)
    - Graham Home Annual Report, 1959; 11800 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
    - Facts about the Graham Home for Children, 1961; 50218 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Uncommon Devotion" fundraising brochure, circa 1966; 50219 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
    - Invitation to Doc Severinsen Benefit for Graham Home, circa 1969; 50220 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
    - Graham Home Annual Report, 1970; 50416 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
    - Spring Tennis Benefit Program, 1973; 11801 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
    - Isabella Graham, Joanna Bethune, Divie Bethune The Power of Faith Exemplified in the Life and Writings of the Late Mrs. Isabella Graham (New York: Kirk and Mercein, 1817), 11803 (Volume 158)
    - Isabella Graham, Joanna Bethune, Divie Bethune The Power of Faith Exemplified in the Life and Writings of the Late Mrs. Isabella Graham, New Edition (New York: American Tract Society, 1843), 11804 (Volume 159)
    - Isabella Graham, Joanna Bethune, Divie Bethune The Unpublished Letters and Correspondence of Mrs. Isabella Graham (New York: John S. Taylor, 1838), 11805 (Volume 160)
    - Joanna H. Mathews, editor A short History of the Orphan Asylum Society (New York: Anson D.F. Randolph and Co., 1892), 11808 (Volume 163)
    - Joanna H. Mathews, editor A short History of the Orphan Asylum Society (New York: Anson D.F. Randolph and Co., 1892), 11809 (Volume 164)
    - Joanna H. Mathews, editor A Short History of the Orphan Asylum Society (New York: Anson D.F. Randolph and Co., 1892), 11810 (Volume 165)
    - Joanna H. Mathews, editor A Short History of the Orphan Asylum Society (New York: Anson D.F. Randolph and Co., 1892) (4 unbound copies), 11811 (Offsite-box 19)
    - Rudolph R. Reeder How Two Hundred Children Live and Learn (Philadelphia: William F. Fell Co., 1909), 11806 (Volume 161)
    - Allan McLane Hamilton The Intimate Life of Alexander Hamilton (London: Duckworth and Co., 1910), 11807 (Volume 162)
    - Franklin Thomas, Ph.D. The Place of the Institution in a Child Welfare Program (4 copies), 1926; 11812 (Offsite-box 19)
    - Franklin Thomas, Ph.D. Environment in Relation to Physical and Mental Health (4 copies), 1930; 11813 (Offsite-box 19)
    - Eugenia Hackshaw, D.P.A. The Applicability of the Eriksonian Model to a Case Management System (4 copies), 1975; 11814 (Offsite-box 19)
    - James O.F. Hackshaw, Ph.D. The Development of a Case Management Instrument to Measure Program Effectiveness (4 copies), 1975; 11815 (Offsite-box 19)
  - Subseries I.9 - Visual Materials, circa 1910-1977, 11437
    The subseries contains three boxes, and two additional folders in an oversize box, containing primarily photographic prints, as well as a smaller quantity of negatives, contact sheets, mock-ups for annual reports and brochures, two loose pages from a photo album, one ink sketch, and some paper materials related to the photographs and interfiled with them.
    Subjects include children and activities at the OAS, benefits and other events, celebrity visitors, and annual report materials. Most photographs were created for publicity purposes or for internal documentation. Photographic formats include prints mounted on board or paper, many sizes of loose prints, and stereoscopic prints. Professional photographers represented in the collection include Alfred J. Merz and Daniel Berry, and there is one print by Lewis Hine. The materials were kept by the Development Department and were arranged by subject and date. Original folder titles have been maintained.
    The subseries also contains one box of wooden printing blocks with negative images used in OAS printed materials circa 1910-1950's, and one scrapbook/photograph album documenting Black Solidarity Week 1974. The printing blocks and the scrapbook are arranged at the end of the subseries.
    - Orphan Asylum on Riverside Drive before 1902 (reprint), undated; 11819 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)